konna koto ii na   dekitara ii na
I wish I had this...   I wish I could do that...
anna yume konna yume  ippai aru kedo
This kind of dream, that kind of dream... There are lots of kinds, but...
minna minna minna   kanaete kureru
Each and every one of them can come true!
fushigi na pokke de kanaete kureru
With his mysterious pocket, he'll make all your dreams come true!
sora wo jiyuu ni tobitai na
I'd sure like to fly about freely in the sky...
"hai! take koputaa"
"All right! Bamboo 'Copter!"
an an an  tottemo daisuki Doraemon
Oh, oh, oh... I love you so much, Doraemon!
Slow-Slow, Quick-Quick
"Slow-Slow, Quick-Quick!"
Man, that Nobita-kun!
He's always
leaving the place so messy!
Oh, Doraemon...!
Huh?
My friend,
Doraemon-kun.
The great
Doraemon-sama...
Here you go.
What?
Here's some dorayaki
that you like so much.
If this is about me doing your
homework, the answer's no!
Aw...
You know me too well...
Well, we do keep going through
the same thing day after day.
But if I don't get your help,
I'll never finish it in time!
And WHY  do you
think it's like that?!
In cases like this, don't you think you need
to really think and reflect over the situation?
Yeah, you're right.
Hmm...
I wonder why...
Why do you think?!
Huh...?
Yeah...
I wonder why?
I can't figure it out just
by thinking in such a hurry.
I'll take my time and think
it over more in detail later!
I'll go out to play now!
You can't do that!
You're always too lax!
I'm going to say this bluntly,
but it's because you're a blockhead!
A dunce!
And on top of that, you're the type
who finds everything bothersome...
You hate studying...
And always depend on
others to do everything for you!
Just suck it up, do what you've
gotta do, and it'll be done in a flash!
What do you mean
I'm a natural blockhead?!
I'm taking this touch stance and saying what
needs to be said today for your sake, Nobita-kun!
Doraemon...
Did you understand what
I'm trying to say, Nobita-kun?
Yeah!
All right! Then
toughen up and go for it!
Yeah, so hurry up and help me!
You'll make it be done in a flash!
Doraemon?
Oww...
Hey, I know! I'll use that!
Let's see here...
Feeling Cologne
It's the "Feeling Cologne: Quick" and the "Feeling Cologne: Slow"!
Quick    Slow
This one's Quick and this one's Slow.
If you use the Quick Cologne, both
your feelings and body will get faster.
And the Slow one does the opposite.
Now, come on... Put a spritz of this on,
and go get your homework done.
Oh, that sounds nice.
I'll do it later.
Augh! Get back here!
I hate cologne.
Does it really  work?
Don't be rude.
Okay, then why don't you test it
out first and show me, Doraemon?
Sure, I can do that...
But it's okay with you, right?
It's fine.
If it's a really good
cologne, I'll use it, too.
All right, if you say so...
D-Doraemon...?
Doraemon?!
Nobi!
Who are you calling "Nobi"?!
Nobita-kun, you're so slow!
Do it!
Hurry, your homework!
Get it done!
You done yet?!
You done yet?! You done yet?!
Huh? Didn't I just sit down?
I'm only just getting started.
You're so slow!
Do it quicker! Quicker!
Gah! I'm really
getting irritated!
So irritating...! Hurry, hurry...!
Gah! So irritating...! Hurry, hurry...!
Doraemon.
Are you done?!
Uh, no. I'd just really like it
if you could calm down a bit.
What're you talking about?!
You're not focusing enough!
Focus! Focus! Focus!
Hup two! Hup two...!
Hup two! Hup two!
Where're you going?!
No, no, you can't skip out!
I'm going to ask Shizuka-chan to
explain the parts I don't understand to me.
Fine! Hurry and get going!
Quickly! Get going! Quickly!
Yeah, yeah.
Whew...
That stuff works TOO well.
Life is meant to
take things easy.
That's it. Just relax
and take things easy.
Hey, welcome back.
I was just going.
What was that?!
Gah! You're so annoying!
I'll take you there!
Hey! You don't
need to go so fast!
What are
you talking about?!
Stop being such a
slow poke and run! Run! Run! Run!
H-Hey!
W-Wait a sec!
I'll ring the doorbell in a jiffy,
then charge in at the same time!
Who is it?
Shizuka-chan, hurry! Hurry!
Huh?
Say "Hi" while you're
taking your shoes off!
Hi!
Is that for tea?!
Thank you, we'll enjoy it!
Ah, but the water's...
Here's tea!
Here, drink! Hurry!
Ew... What IS  this?!
And I'll fart before
I eat the roasted sweet potato!
And now we're done eating, so bye!
But I still have things
I need to do there...
What?!
What?! What ?!
What were you doing then?!
Unbelievable! Unbelievable!
Unbelievable! What were you doing?!
Unbelievable! Unbelievable! Gah!
Whoa!
Okay, Doraemon! I got it!
I got it, so can you
stop for a second?!
I'm begging you. Please use the
Slow Cologne and go back to normal.
At this rate, I'll never be able to
concentrate on my homework.
Okay, did you... Get the feeling...
to do your homework on your own?!
Did you?! Did you?! Did you?!
I did, I did, I did.
In that case,
I'll go back to normal!
There it is!
Wait, isn't that "Quick"?
Huh?
Quick
Get the Slow! Get the Slow!
Ah, there it is.
Here.
This is a problem! This is a problem!
Huh?
Come on!
Gimme it! Gimme it!
Yeah, I'm trying.
It's no use! Now that
I've started running, I can't stop!
Someone stop me!
Doraemon!
Hurry!
Catch me! Catch me!
What're you doing?
What're you doing? You dummy!
This is hopeless.
I've gotta put
on some Quick, too.
This one's Quick. This one's Slow.
He sure is dumb to
get them mixed up.
Oh, no!
I mixed them up!
I needed this one!
Oh... well...
If... I... leave... him... be...
It's...cologne...so...
it'll...wear...off...eventually...
Right...?
I'll...go...home...
What was
that wind just now?
D-D-Did N-N-Nobita-kun
come home yet?
It doesn't seem like
he has, yet, but why?
Man, I'm
getting exhausted...
My body's worn out, but
I'm running on pure adrenaline!
If I don't hurry and put some of that
Slow Cologne on, I'm going to break!
What...?
Like...I...would...lose...to...you...?
This escargot is
absolutely superb.
Huh?
No...matter...how...
you...look...at...me...
I'm...really...fast...
But...it...looks...
like...I'm...gonna...lose...
I'll...do...my...best...
'Ey, Nobita.
What are you doing?
I'm...racing...
Against...a...snail...
What?!
I...lost...
You're...really...fast...!
But ya' know, dey say
frogs're pretty tasty, too.
'N dere are bunches of
'em in da school pond...
Huh?!
Gian, Suneo...
Gian... Suneo...
Tell me! Tell me! Tell me! Hurry!
Tell me! Hurry!
Tell you what?
About Nobita, of course!
Don't you know? Don't you know?
Hurry, tell me!
I said hurry, tell me!
Quickly! Quickly!
If ya' wanna
know 'bout Nobita...
Gah! You're SO
slow, I can't stand it!
Enough! I'll just
look for him myself!
Wut da...?
I...am...home...
What are you doing,
standing out here?
He said he was waiting for
someone to open the door for him.
I wonder if he tired
himself out by playing?
Nobi-chan, you're
going to spill these.
What's that? Some
kind of perfume sample?
Let me see it.
Uh...
Mmm... It has a
really nice fragrance.
Um...
What is it?
That...is...
I can't wait all day.
Hurry up and spit it out.
What does it smell like?
Let me try some, too.
Ah...
I'm...too...late...
It finally wore off.
Aomori is 715 kilometers from Tokyo.
I ran all the way to Aomori...
Huh?
Don't tell me that...
I work, then "good morning",
then "I'm going home".
I'll do tomorrow's
shopping before dinner.
Come here. This time,
put on some Slow, and...
Wait, wait!
Man! You guys are all so loud,
I can't concentrate on my homework!
Mini Theater
I never want to see
Gian's face ever again!
Pull out some gadget that makes it so
you'll never see a person you don't like!
If you wave this with your right hand,
it'll make any other person get away from you.
Just like this.
And to cancel it, you
do it with your left hand.
If you don't cancel it, you'll never
be able to see them again for all eternity.
'Ey, Nobita!
And with that, I can live
without ever seeing Gian again!
You never do
your homework!
And that gets rid of
one more scary person.
Now I think I'll go
play as long as I want.
Where did you drop it?
If you don't cancel it with that handkerchief,
Mom will never come home, for all eternity!
Nobita's Wife
"Nobita's Wife!"
Nobi!
Do you mind telling me
why you got this terrible score?!
Dreams for your future
When you grow up, you're going to be entering
the workforce and getting married, right?
What do you think your
children will be saying about you?
Do you want them to say "My dad
always got nothing but zeroes"?
Nobi! Are you listening to me?!
Hey, what are you gonna
be when you grow up?
I'm gonna be a nurse!
I'm going to be a wife!
Oh? Whose~?
Oh, I don't know that, yet~!
If I get married, I hope it's to a girl
like that pop star, Marui Mari-chan.
What's wrong, Gian?
Well, Ma wuz talkin' ta me...
'N she said "If you get married, it needs to
be a burly girl, strong enough to lift a dresser".
Dun laff 'bout it!
Whoa, wait!
Before all that, you don't even know
whether you CAN  get married or not, right?
Ah... Well, dat's true.
Are ya' sayin' dat I can't get married?!
Den wut about YOU ?!
I-I can get married,
just like I'm supposed to.
Nobita getting married?!
Dere ain't no way sumone who gets nuttin'
but zeroes like ya' could ever get married!
Time sure flies by, doesn't it?
Kindergarten
It seems like it was just yesterday
that he was starting kindergarten...
School Entrance Ceremony
And before you know it,
he's an elementary schooler.
And pretty soon,
he'll be a middle schooler.
And then right after that,
he'll start high school and college.
Well... If he can
even get accepted to one.
Oh?
Ah! Are these Mom
and Dad's wedding pictures?!
Wow... These really take me back.
What's wrong?
I wonder if the day when Nobita takes a bride will ever come...
Well...
I'm home.
Oh?!
Welcome back!
I wonder what's wrong?
Oh, I get it.
What if...
Just what if I can't
get married? What do I do?
Come on... Are you
seriously that worried about it?
Yeah.
Well, if you're that worried
about it, why don't we go see?
Go see... what?
Go see your future
wife in the Time Machine!
What?!
No way! Just thinking of
it is making me so embarrassed!
Then I'll drop the subject.
No, I really, really  wanna see!
Which one is it?!
Let's go 25 years in the future!
By that time, even someone as
useless as you will have found someone...
The "someone as useless
as you" part was uncalled for!
Huh?
We popped out in the bathroom.
Hmm... The place
must have been rebuilt.
Oh, so that's it.
Huh...?
What is it this time?
There's nothing but bathrooms.
My house turned
into a public restroom.
Huh?
Hmm... It looks like this
area was turned into a park.
Then, where's my house?
Whoa, awesome! That's so cool!
Wow! All the cars
zipping by look so cool!
It's a police box!
Let's try asking there.
Oh...
That area was turned into
a park about ten years ago.
Oh, is that right?
Let me see... You're
looking for Nobi-san, correct?
Nobi Nobita-kun, the scatterbrained
guy who can't do anything right!
Nobi Nobita-san lives over there.
He moved to that
high-rise apartment building.
He's on the 12th floor, apartment 68.
Thank you for your help.
The way the town looks
has completely changed.
Wow! If I can live in a place like this...
Maybe I've become rich?
That'd be nice, wouldn't it?
This is it.
W-Wait a minute.
O-On second thought,
meeting them is a bad idea.
Well, I guess that's true.
I wanna just sneak a peek
at them from the shadows.
All right. I'll let you
borrow the X-Ray Glass.
It lets you be able to
see through any kind of wall.
And I can see them with this?
But even if this
is my own house...
Peeking in is
really bad, isn't it~?
Oh, what should I do~?!
Then give it back.
No, I'll look!
Ah!
There she is!
There she is, Doraemon!
It's my wife!
She was really there!
That's great.
So what kind of person is she?
I could only
see her from behind.
What's wrong?
No, yuck!
She's scary-looking!
You can tell me that, but
what am I supposed to do about it?
They are certainly taking a long time!
Where could they have possibly gone?
No, no!
Do something, Doraemon!
But you see, now you
know you're able to get married.
Right? Isn't that great?
Right?!
No! It'd be better
to NOT get married!
I know! Let's look
a little closer! Okay?!
Let's see... Where's a place
where we can get a closer look...?
No matter where I look
from, she'll still be the same!
There. I caught you!
Come with me, young man!
N-No, I don't wanna!
Knock it off!
Nobita-kun...
Wait! You've got
the wrong person!
You're always, always
making my poor Sunetaro cry!
I apologize. Our Nobisuke is a very
naughty boy, and he tends to act up.
"Our Nobisuke..."?
Go on! You need to
apologize, too, young man.
Please punish him very well!
I really, truly apologize
for the trouble he caused you.
Shizuka-san! This is because
you don't keep him under control.
Shizuka-san?!
Honestly!
I apologize.
C-Could it be...?!
Is this Shizuka-chan,
25 years in the future...?
This "Nobisuke" has a
face that looks just like mine.
That would mean... he's my son!
And Shizuka-chan is his mom!
So that means...
That means... That means...
That means...!
By any chance, are you
Minamoto Shizuka-san?
Why are you asking
something so obvious?
All right!
I see! So it was you!
So that's who it was!
Oh, I'm SO happy!
What is with you, looking
at your mom like that?!
I'm so happy...!
Your father is such a quiet,
carefree, obedient person...
So why are you
such an unruly child?!
What are you doing? Stop it!
You've got
the wrong person!
I'm home!
What...?
W-What are you doing?
You see?!
That's Nobisuke!
What...?!
There are two Nobisukes?
Who are you?!
And what are you doing here?!
Nobisuke! You mustn't be so violent!
And are you studying,
like you're supposed to?!
Mom! This guy's an alien!
He took my form, and
came to take over our house!
Hey! Look at your father
when he's speaking to you!
What do you mean, "father"?!
Father?!
Hey! Cut it out!
Oh... Nobita-kun sure
is taking a long time.
Huh?
Run, Doraemon!
Wait, Nobita-kun!
Come back here!
Dora-chan...?
Doraemon, let's hurry
back to the Time Machine!
He's after us!
Oh, no!
Someone's in there!
What're we gonna do, Doraemon?!
Where are you?!
We're begging you! Please
hurry up in there and come out!
So THIS  is where you were...?
You alien fiends have
nowhere else to run!
Oh, no!
He's gonna get us!
What a violent boy...
Well, at least he's energetic, right?
But to think that I
marry Shizuka-chan!
But the future might change, so....
I know. I'll work hard to
become a really great grown-up...
So then I'll marry Shizuka-chan!
That's the spirit!
Nobita!
Shizuka-chan's here.
Sorry to impose on you!
Hey, Nobita-san!
Huh?
Why is he all shy and
embarrassed like that?
Sure is a strange boy.